

RICHIE HOLSENBACK

FRONT-END DESIGN

CONTACT

RICHIEHOLSENBACK.GITHUB.IO/
(334)707-9242
RICHIEHOLSENBACK@GMAIL.COM
GITHUB.COM/RICHIEHOLSENBACK
LINKEDIN.COM/IN/RICHIE-HOLSENBACK

SKILLS AND RELEVANT CLASSES

Tech Stack:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Javascript
- ReactJS
- Git and GitHub
- Visual Studio Code
- NPM
- JSON Server
- Firebase
- Figma
- SASS
- Bootstrap
- Semantic UI

Experienced in:

- Prototyping
- Wire framing
- Information Architecture
- User and Usability Testing
- Journey Mapping

The Adobe Creative Suite, including:

- Photoshop
- Lightroom
- Illustrator
- Premiere Pro
- After Effects
- Audition
- InDesign

ABOUT ME

I am a creative minded UI/UX designer with experience in React, Javascript, HTML, CSS and Sass. I enjoy working with teams to create attractive and functional applications that are user focused and user tested. I pride myself in being adaptable, being a team player and having strong leadership skills.

Before beginning a career in UI/UX Design, I worked in digital media and social media marketing. I love the marrying of creative and technical mindedness that those fields require. UI/UX design has offered a way to further the skills I obtained from those roles in the best way. The ever-expanding space to grow and learn as a designer and developer is the thing that makes me most excited about the future in this industry.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

FRONT-END UI/UX DEVELOPER | AUGUST 2020 - PRESENT

- Develop dynamic single-page applications using React in addition to modern ES6+ JavaScript
- Learned fundamentals such as HTML, CSS, JSON, modular code, reusable components, database structure and using Entity Relationship Diagrams
- Work with team members to create sites with user experience in mind, lead user testing sessions in order to gain knowledge on how to improve user interface and enhance the site based on those results
- Exposed to an Agile environment through frequent group projects including daily stand ups, planning, ticket assignments and problem solving
- Used Githib to perform and review pull requests to ensure working code free of merge conflicts

PERSONAL PROJECTS

LAUGH TRACK

GITHUB.COM/RICHIEHOLSENBACK/LAUGHTRACK

Laugh Track is a React-based web application in which comedians can create and engage with a community, workshop new material or improve older jokes and showcase events they are hosting. The project came from market research in what would help comedians improve and become as successful as possible with tools to help network, organize and showcase their talent.

OURFLIX

RICHIEHOLSENBACK.GITHUB.IO/OURFLIX

Ourflix is another React JS based-web application designed to help users skip the hour long conversation of, "What should we watch tonight?" Users can log in through firebase, become friends, swipe through a library of movies and shows on Netflix to determine what they're interested in watching, and compare what movies they have both liked. You can get details about the movies, check out the IMDB page or head straight to Netflix to watch the movie or show.

GROUP PROJECTS

C43 CLASS WEBSITE

NSS-DAY-COHORT-43.GITHUB.IO/

The C43 Class site was a project for the Nashville Software School. We needed an attractive, functional site to display the many talented individuals in out cohort. We created user personas, wireframes, and mockups then user tested our design. When we had a final design, our team divided up the tasks to be completed and worked as a team to code the site into being. I worked on the technology section and organized the database of technology learned and the student information.

NUTTYSHELL

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/NSS-DAY-COHORT-43/HALLO-TWEEN-TOWN

This project was completed twice, the first round was a collaboration between 4 team members using traditional JavaScript, HTML and CSS. The Second round utilized React JavaScript as well as component libraries to help with styling. We created a wireframe, an ERD and group coded the welcome page and overall design of the site.

- In the first round, I was responsible for creating the events section of the app. The section hit MVP when a user could create an event with a title, location, date, time and description of that event. They must also be able to edit or delete their own events entirely.
- In the second round, I utilized React to create a dynamic messaging feature. This section hit MVP when a user could send a message that all other users could view in an updating feed. The user was also able to delete their own messages, but not those of another user.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SMILE DIRECT CLUB

SOCIAL MEDIA/ONLINE-CONTENT SPECIALIST | OCT 2019 - AUG 2020

- Create and design online content geared towards a variety of customers keeping multi-device design in mind
- Maintain content on all social channels, including Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Pinterest and LinkedIn
- Work with web development team to create content that worked with site design and layout

CUSTOMER CARE FLOOR SUPPORT/SPECIALIST | APR 2018 - OCT 2019

- · Provide team members with assistance regarding company standard operating procedures, software and specialty cases
- Created solutions and procedures that ensured that customers were being assisted as efficiently as possible, decreasing time spent on cases by team members
- Follow up with customers to find solutions more geared towards their individual desires

GOTTA GUY MARKETING

MARKETING ASSOCIATE | JAN 2018 - DEC 2018

- Create advertisement material that recipients find informational and attractive
- · Maintain a social media presents for dozens of insurance agents with informative and engaging posts
- Monitor engagement and activity on posts to gauge success of campaigns

RICHIE HOLSENBACK PRODUCTIONS

OWNER | MAY 2015 - PRESENT

- Film and edit visually and emotionally moving videos for clients
- Create and maintain a customer base, communicate with them to solve any creative differences or problems
- · Maintain a social media presence to be aesthetically pleasing and inviting to new customers

EDUCATION

UI/UX DESIGNER. FRONT END DEVELOPER

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | AUG 2020 - PRESENT

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, MAJOR IN FINANCE

AUBURN UNIVERSITY | AUG 2011 - MAY 2016